Close Search

Search for:  Search

[

](https://www.rugeleyrifleclub.org.uk/)

Menu

* More

Search for:  Search

Open Search

Website Privacy Policy
======================

Effective: Nov 4th 2021

Rugeley Rifle Club (“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates the https://www.rugeleyrifleclub.org.uk website.

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.

#### **Definitions**

**Personal Data**

Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).

**Usage Data**

Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).

**Cookies**

Cookies are small pieces of data stored on a User’s device.

**Data Controller**

Data Controller means a person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal data are, or are to be, processed.

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your data.

**Data Processor (or Service Providers)**

Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any person (other than an employee of the Data Controller) who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.

We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.

**Data Subject**

Data Subject is any living individual who is the subject of Personal Data.

**User**

The User is the individual using our Service. The User corresponds to the Data Subject, who is the subject of Personal Data.

**Information Collection And Use**

We collect several different types of anonymised and personal information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.

#### **Types of Data Collected**

**Personal Data**

Any personal data that you provide via email will only be used by officers of Rugeley Rifle Club for the purpose that you have requested.

This data will only be retained for as long as is necessary to attend to your enquiry and will not be passed on to a third party.

**Usage Data**

We may also collect information regarding how the Service is accessed and used (“Usage Data”) via Matomo Analytics. Matomo Analytics is a web analytics service that tracks and reports website traffic. Matomo is hosted locally to the Service and data is not shared with any third party. We do not wish to track users identifiably, merely see which pages receive the most traffic and understanding how the site is used. Matomo is configured to collect broadly anonymised data including:

* The first two bytes of your computer’s Internet Protocol address (e.g. 152.120.153.25 becomes 152.120.0.0)
* Browser type & version
* The time and date of your visit
* The pages of our Service that you visit
* The time spent on those pages
* Referrer URL (not including query strings)
* Other diagnostic data

Individual visit data is deleted after 180 days, leaving only aggregated statistics.

**Tracking Cookies Data**

We do not use cookies to track activity on our Service.

**Use of Data**

Rugeley Rifle Club uses the collected data for various purposes:

* To provide and maintain our Service
* To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service
* To monitor the usage of our Service
* To detect, prevent and address technical issues

#### **Retention of Data**

Rugeley Rifle Club will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

Rugeley Rifle Club will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.

#### **Transfer Of Data**

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located in the United Kingdom.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Rugeley Rifle Club will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

#### **Disclosure Of Data**

**Disclosure for Law Enforcement**

Under certain circumstances, Rugeley Rifle Club may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).

**Legal Requirements**

Rugeley Rifle Club may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

• To comply with a legal obligation

• To protect and defend the rights or property of Rugeley Rifle Club

• To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service

• To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public

• To protect against legal liability

#### **Security Of Data**

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

#### **“Do Not Track” Signals**

Matomo Analytics is configured to support Do Not Track (“DNT”). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

#### **Your Rights**

Rugeley Rifle Club aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.

If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the right:

• To access and receive a copy of the Personal Data we hold about you

• To rectify any Personal Data held about you that is inaccurate

• To request the deletion of Personal Data held about you

You have the right to data portability for the information you provide to Rugeley Rifle Club. You can request to obtain a copy of your Personal Data in a commonly used electronic format so that you can manage and move it.

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

#### **Links To Other Sites**

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

#### **Children’s Privacy**

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 13 (“Children”).

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

#### **Changes To This Privacy Policy**

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

We will update the “effective date” at the top of this Privacy Policy.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

#### **Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email: admin@rugeleyrifleclub.org.uk

[

](https://www.nsra.co.uk/)  
  
[

](https://www.nsra.co.uk/)  
  
[

](https://www.britishshooting.org.uk/)

Copyright Rugeley Rifle Club © 2024 All Rights Reserved. [Website Privacy Policy](https://www.rugeleyrifleclub.org.uk/website-privacy-policy)
